[
    {
        "question_no.": 1,
        "Question": "What event is widely considered the trigger for the start of World War I?",
        "Option1": "The sinking of the Lusitania",
        "Option2": "The assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand",
        "Option3": "Germany's invasion of Poland",
        "Option4": "The Battle of Stalingrad",
        "Answer": "The assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 2,
        "Question": "Which country was NOT a member of the Triple Entente in World War I?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Russia",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 3,
        "Question": "In what year did World War I begin?",
        "Option1": "1912",
        "Option2": "1914",
        "Option3": "1916",
        "Option4": "1918",
        "Answer": "1914"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 4,
        "Question": "What was the main form of combat on the Western Front during WWI?",
        "Option1": "Guerrilla warfare",
        "Option2": "Aerial combat",
        "Option3": "Trench warfare",
        "Option4": "Naval battles",
        "Answer": "Trench warfare"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 5,
        "Question": "What was the name of the treaty that officially ended World War I?",
        "Option1": "Treaty of Paris",
        "Option2": "Treaty of Trianon",
        "Option3": "Treaty of Versailles",
        "Option4": "Treaty of Brest-Litovsk",
        "Answer": "Treaty of Versailles"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 6,
        "Question": "Which country was the last to join the Allied Powers in WWI?",
        "Option1": "United States",
        "Option2": "Japan",
        "Option3": "Italy",
        "Option4": "Ottoman Empire",
        "Answer": "United States"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 7,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of Germany during World War I?",
        "Option1": "Adolf Hitler",
        "Option2": "Otto von Bismarck",
        "Option3": "Kaiser Wilhelm II",
        "Option4": "Paul von Hindenburg",
        "Answer": "Kaiser Wilhelm II"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 8,
        "Question": "What new technology was first used on a large scale in WWI?",
        "Option1": "The nuclear bomb",
        "Option2": "The radar",
        "Option3": "Tanks",
        "Option4": "Submarines",
        "Answer": "Tanks"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 9,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German war plan for WWI?",
        "Option1": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option2": "Schlieffen Plan",
        "Option3": "Operation Overlord",
        "Option4": "The Battle of Britain",
        "Answer": "Schlieffen Plan"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 10,
        "Question": "The Treaty of Versailles required Germany to pay large sums of money, known as what?",
        "Option1": "Taxes",
        "Option2": "Reparations",
        "Option3": "Tariffs",
        "Option4": "Bonds",
        "Answer": "Reparations"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 11,
        "Question": "What major event happened in Russia during WWI that led to its withdrawal from the war?",
        "Option1": "A civil war",
        "Option2": "The Bolshevik Revolution",
        "Option3": "A military coup",
        "Option4": "A famine",
        "Answer": "The Bolshevik Revolution"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 12,
        "Question": "The sinking of which British ocean liner by a German U-boat in 1915 angered the United States?",
        "Option1": "Titanic",
        "Option2": "Queen Mary",
        "Option3": "Lusitania",
        "Option4": "Britannic",
        "Answer": "Lusitania"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 13,
        "Question": "What was the name of the peace-keeping organization formed after WWI?",
        "Option1": "United Nations",
        "Option2": "League of Nations",
        "Option3": "NATO",
        "Option4": "Red Cross",
        "Answer": "League of Nations"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 14,
        "Question": "The term 'no man's land' refers to the area between which two WWI military positions?",
        "Option1": "The fronts of two navies",
        "Option2": "The lines of opposing trenches",
        "Option3": "The sky between two air forces",
        "Option4": "The land between two countries",
        "Answer": "The lines of opposing trenches"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 15,
        "Question": "Which nation was NOT a part of the Central Powers during WWI?",
        "Option1": "Austria-Hungary",
        "Option2": "Germany",
        "Option3": "Ottoman Empire",
        "Option4": "Italy",
        "Answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 16,
        "Question": "What was the date of the armistice that ended the fighting in WWI?",
        "Option1": "December 25, 1918",
        "Option2": "November 11, 1918",
        "Option3": "October 31, 1918",
        "Option4": "January 1, 1919",
        "Answer": "November 11, 1918"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 17,
        "Question": "Which of the following was a reason for the United States' entry into WWI?",
        "Option1": "Attack on a military base",
        "Option2": "The Zimmerman Telegram",
        "Option3": "Germany's invasion of France",
        "Option4": "The Russian Revolution",
        "Answer": "The Zimmerman Telegram"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 18,
        "Question": "What was the name of the Serbian nationalist group that assassinated Archduke Franz Ferdinand?",
        "Option1": "The Red Army",
        "Option2": "The Black Hand",
        "Option3": "The Iron Cross",
        "Option4": "The German Workers' Party",
        "Answer": "The Black Hand"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 19,
        "Question": "Which battle of WWI is known for its massive casualties and is often a symbol of the futility of trench warfare?",
        "Option1": "Battle of the Marne",
        "Option2": "Battle of Verdun",
        "Option3": "Battle of the Somme",
        "Option4": "First Battle of Ypres",
        "Answer": "Battle of the Somme"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 20,
        "Question": "The Treaty of Versailles required Germany to give up territory to which country?",
        "Option1": "United States",
        "Option2": "Soviet Union",
        "Option3": "France",
        "Option4": "Italy",
        "Answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 21,
        "Question": "Which of the following was a new weapon used in WWI?",
        "Option1": "Crossbows",
        "Option2": "Poison gas",
        "Option3": "Cannons",
        "Option4": "Flamethrowers",
        "Answer": "Poison gas"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 22,
        "Question": "In what year did World War II begin?",
        "Option1": "1938",
        "Option2": "1939",
        "Option3": "1941",
        "Option4": "1945",
        "Answer": "1939"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 23,
        "Question": "What event is considered the start of WWII in Europe?",
        "Option1": "Germany's invasion of Poland",
        "Option2": "The bombing of Pearl Harbor",
        "Option3": "The Battle of Britain",
        "Option4": "The signing of the Treaty of Versailles",
        "Answer": "Germany's invasion of Poland"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 24,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of the Soviet Union during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option2": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option3": "Leon Trotsky",
        "Option4": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Answer": "Joseph Stalin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 25,
        "Question": "Which country was NOT a member of the Axis Powers?",
        "Option1": "Germany",
        "Option2": "Japan",
        "Option3": "Italy",
        "Option4": "Soviet Union",
        "Answer": "Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 26,
        "Question": "The surprise attack on Pearl Harbor happened on what date?",
        "Option1": "December 7, 1941",
        "Option2": "June 6, 1944",
        "Option3": "September 1, 1939",
        "Option4": "May 8, 1945",
        "Answer": "December 7, 1941"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 27,
        "Question": "What was the name of the Nazi extermination camps where millions of Jews were murdered?",
        "Option1": "Gulags",
        "Option2": "Concentration camps",
        "Option3": "Exile camps",
        "Option4": "Refugee camps",
        "Answer": "Concentration camps"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 28,
        "Question": "The D-Day invasion took place on which beach?",
        "Option1": "Omaha Beach",
        "Option2": "Iwo Jima",
        "Option3": "Normandy Beach",
        "Option4": "Pebble Beach",
        "Answer": "Normandy Beach"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 29,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German Air Force during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Panzerwaffe",
        "Option2": "Kriegsmarine",
        "Option3": "Luftwaffe",
        "Option4": "Wehrmacht",
        "Answer": "Luftwaffe"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 30,
        "Question": "The Battle of Britain was fought primarily with what?",
        "Option1": "Tanks",
        "Option2": "Ships",
        "Option3": "Submarines",
        "Option4": "Aircraft",
        "Answer": "Aircraft"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 31,
        "Question": "What was the term for Germany's lightning-fast military strategy?",
        "Option1": "Sitzkrieg",
        "Option2": "Blitzkrieg",
        "Option3": "Lebensraum",
        "Option4": "Anschluss",
        "Answer": "Blitzkrieg"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 32,
        "Question": "Who was the Prime Minister of Great Britain during most of WWII?",
        "Option1": "Neville Chamberlain",
        "Option2": "Winston Churchill",
        "Option3": "Clement Attlee",
        "Option4": "Tony Blair",
        "Answer": "Winston Churchill"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 33,
        "Question": "The Manhattan Project was the code name for the development of what?",
        "Option1": "The Enigma machine",
        "Option2": "The atomic bomb",
        "Option3": "Jet engines",
        "Option4": "Radar technology",
        "Answer": "The atomic bomb"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 34,
        "Question": "What was the name of the final major German offensive on the Western Front in WWII?",
        "Option1": "Battle of the Bulge",
        "Option2": "Battle of Normandy",
        "Option3": "Battle of the Ruhr",
        "Option4": "Battle of Stalingrad",
        "Answer": "Battle of the Bulge"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 35,
        "Question": "Which city was the first to be hit by an atomic bomb?",
        "Option1": "Tokyo",
        "Option2": "Hiroshima",
        "Option3": "Nagasaki",
        "Option4": "Kyoto",
        "Answer": "Hiroshima"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 36,
        "Question": "What was the main purpose of the United Nations, founded after WWII?",
        "Option1": "To create a global currency",
        "Option2": "To prevent future wars",
        "Option3": "To control global trade",
        "Option4": "To promote specific political ideologies",
        "Answer": "To prevent future wars"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 37,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German invasion of the Soviet Union?",
        "Option1": "Operation Sealion",
        "Option2": "Operation Torch",
        "Option3": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option4": "Operation Overlord",
        "Answer": "Operation Barbarossa"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 38,
        "Question": "Which country signed a non-aggression pact with Nazi Germany in 1939, only to be invaded later?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Poland",
        "Option3": "Soviet Union",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 39,
        "Question": "What was the name given to the German air raids on British cities during WWII?",
        "Option1": "The Blitz",
        "Option2": "The Pounding",
        "Option3": "The Storm",
        "Option4": "The Bombardment",
        "Answer": "The Blitz"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 40,
        "Question": "The Japanese attack on Pearl Harbor led to the US entering which war?",
        "Option1": "World War I",
        "Option2": "World War II",
        "Option3": "The Cold War",
        "Option4": "Korean War",
        "Answer": "World War II"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 41,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of the US during the attack on Pearl Harbor?",
        "Option1": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Option2": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option3": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option4": "Woodrow Wilson",
        "Answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 42,
        "Question": "Which of the following was NOT a member of the Allied Powers in WWII?",
        "Option1": "United States",
        "Option2": "Soviet Union",
        "Option3": "France",
        "Option4": "Italy",
        "Answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 43,
        "Question": "The Battle of Stalingrad was a turning point on which front?",
        "Option1": "Western Front",
        "Option2": "Eastern Front",
        "Option3": "Pacific Front",
        "Option4": "African Front",
        "Answer": "Eastern Front"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 44,
        "Question": "What was the name of the major naval battle in the Pacific theater between the US and Japan?",
        "Option1": "Battle of the Atlantic",
        "Option2": "Battle of Midway",
        "Option3": "Battle of the Coral Sea",
        "Option4": "Battle of Okinawa",
        "Answer": "Battle of Midway"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 45,
        "Question": "The genocide of approximately six million Jews by the Nazi regime is known as what?",
        "Option1": "The Great Purge",
        "Option2": "The Holocaust",
        "Option3": "The Final Solution",
        "Option4": "The Great Famine",
        "Answer": "The Holocaust"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 46,
        "Question": "Which city was the site of the war crimes tribunals after WWII?",
        "Option1": "Paris",
        "Option2": "London",
        "Option3": "Nuremberg",
        "Option4": "Tokyo",
        "Answer": "Nuremberg"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 47,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German defense line on the French coast?",
        "Option1": "Maginot Line",
        "Option2": "Siegfried Line",
        "Option3": "Atlantic Wall",
        "Option4": "Gustav Line",
        "Answer": "Atlantic Wall"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 48,
        "Question": "Who was the Supreme Commander of the Allied Expeditionary Force in Europe during WWII?",
        "Option1": "George S. Patton",
        "Option2": "Douglas MacArthur",
        "Option3": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option4": "Bernard Montgomery",
        "Answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 49,
        "Question": "What was the name of the Allied invasion of North Africa in WWII?",
        "Option1": "Operation Torch",
        "Option2": "Operation Overlord",
        "Option3": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option4": "Operation Sealion",
        "Answer": "Operation Torch"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 50,
        "Question": "The Japanese surrender in WWII was signed aboard which US battleship?",
        "Option1": "USS Arizona",
        "Option2": "USS Missouri",
        "Option3": "USS Enterprise",
        "Option4": "USS Lexington",
        "Answer": "USS Missouri"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 51,
        "Question": "What term refers to the period after the German invasion of Poland when there was little fighting?",
        "Option1": "Blitzkrieg",
        "Option2": "Sitzkrieg",
        "Option3": "Phony War",
        "Option4": "Stalingrad",
        "Answer": "Phony War"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 52,
        "Question": "The Battle of Stalingrad was fought in which country?",
        "Option1": "Germany",
        "Option2": "Poland",
        "Option3": "Soviet Union",
        "Option4": "France",
        "Answer": "Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 53,
        "Question": "Who was the US President who authorized the use of atomic bombs on Japan?",
        "Option1": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option2": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Option3": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option4": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Answer": "Harry S. Truman"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 54,
        "Question": "The policy of appeasement was primarily aimed at avoiding war with which country?",
        "Option1": "Italy",
        "Option2": "Japan",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Soviet Union",
        "Answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 55,
        "Question": "Which of the following was a new invention that helped the British in the Battle of Britain?",
        "Option1": "Radar",
        "Option2": "Jet engines",
        "Option3": "Nuclear submarines",
        "Option4": "Stealth bombers",
        "Answer": "Radar"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 56,
        "Question": "What was the name of the first concentration camp established by the Nazis?",
        "Option1": "Auschwitz",
        "Option2": "Dachau",
        "Option3": "Treblinka",
        "Option4": "Sachsenhausen",
        "Answer": "Dachau"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 57,
        "Question": "What event brought the US into World War II?",
        "Option1": "The sinking of the Lusitania",
        "Option2": "The attack on Pearl Harbor",
        "Option3": "The invasion of Poland",
        "Option4": "The Battle of Britain",
        "Answer": "The attack on Pearl Harbor"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 58,
        "Question": "The Battle of Normandy is also known as what?",
        "Option1": "Operation Torch",
        "Option2": "Operation Overlord",
        "Option3": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option4": "The Battle of the Bulge",
        "Answer": "Operation Overlord"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 59,
        "Question": "Which Axis country surrendered first in WWII?",
        "Option1": "Germany",
        "Option2": "Italy",
        "Option3": "Japan",
        "Option4": "Hungary",
        "Answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 60,
        "Question": "The Yalta Conference involved the leaders of which three countries?",
        "Option1": "United States, Soviet Union, Great Britain",
        "Option2": "Germany, Italy, Japan",
        "Option3": "United States, France, Italy",
        "Option4": "Germany, United States, Great Britain",
        "Answer": "United States, Soviet Union, Great Britain"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 61,
        "Question": "What was the purpose of the 'Final Solution'?",
        "Option1": "To win the war quickly",
        "Option2": "To expand German territory",
        "Option3": "The Nazi plan to exterminate all Jews",
        "Option4": "To create a new form of government",
        "Answer": "The Nazi plan to exterminate all Jews"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 62,
        "Question": "The Berlin airlift was a post-WWII event that took place in which city?",
        "Option1": "Berlin",
        "Option2": "London",
        "Option3": "Moscow",
        "Option4": "Paris",
        "Answer": "Berlin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 63,
        "Question": "What was the main purpose of the Potsdam Conference?",
        "Option1": "To plan the D-Day invasion",
        "Option2": "To decide how to administer post-war Germany",
        "Option3": "To declare war on Japan",
        "Option4": "To form the United Nations",
        "Answer": "To decide how to administer post-war Germany"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 64,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of the Allied forces in the Pacific during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option2": "Douglas MacArthur",
        "Option3": "George Patton",
        "Option4": "Chester Nimitz",
        "Answer": "Douglas MacArthur"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 65,
        "Question": "The term 'kamikaze' refers to what in WWII?",
        "Option1": "Japanese suicide pilots",
        "Option2": "A type of Japanese tank",
        "Option3": "A Japanese naval vessel",
        "Option4": "A type of Japanese samurai",
        "Answer": "Japanese suicide pilots"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 66,
        "Question": "The Holocaust targeted which of the following groups?",
        "Option1": "Jews",
        "Option2": "Roma",
        "Option3": "Homosexuals",
        "Option4": "All of the above",
        "Answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 67,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German secret police during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Gestapo",
        "Option2": "SS",
        "Option3": "SA",
        "Option4": "Wehrmacht",
        "Answer": "Gestapo"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 68,
        "Question": "The Battle of the Atlantic was fought primarily between whom?",
        "Option1": "British and German naval forces",
        "Option2": "US and Japanese naval forces",
        "Option3": "German and Soviet forces",
        "Option4": "British and French forces",
        "Answer": "British and German naval forces"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 69,
        "Question": "What was the code name for the D-Day invasion?",
        "Option1": "Operation Torch",
        "Option2": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option3": "Operation Overlord",
        "Option4": "Operation Sealion",
        "Answer": "Operation Overlord"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 70,
        "Question": "The Treaty of Versailles is often cited as a major cause of which war?",
        "Option1": "World War I",
        "Option2": "The Cold War",
        "Option3": "The Korean War",
        "Option4": "World War II",
        "Answer": "World War II"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 71,
        "Question": "What was the name of the Italian dictator during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Benito Mussolini",
        "Option2": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option3": "Francisco Franco",
        "Option4": "Antonio Salazar",
        "Answer": "Benito Mussolini"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 72,
        "Question": "Which country was the first to successfully develop a nuclear weapon?",
        "Option1": "Soviet Union",
        "Option2": "Great Britain",
        "Option3": "United States",
        "Option4": "Germany",
        "Answer": "United States"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 73,
        "Question": "The United States provided war materials to Allied nations through what program before officially entering WWII?",
        "Option1": "The Marshall Plan",
        "Option2": "The Lend-Lease Act",
        "Option3": "The Monroe Doctrine",
        "Option4": "The Fourteen Points",
        "Answer": "The Lend-Lease Act"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 74,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German-speaking area of Czechoslovakia that Hitler demanded?",
        "Option1": "The Rhineland",
        "Option2": "The Sudetenland",
        "Option3": "The Polish Corridor",
        "Option4": "The Baltic States",
        "Answer": "The Sudetenland"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 75,
        "Question": "The Battle of the Bulge took place in which country?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Belgium",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Soviet Union",
        "Answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 76,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of the Fascist Party in Italy?",
        "Option1": "Adolf Hitler",
        "Option2": "Benito Mussolini",
        "Option3": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option4": "Francisco Franco",
        "Answer": "Benito Mussolini"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 77,
        "Question": "The 'Maginot Line' was a series of fortifications built by which country?",
        "Option1": "Germany",
        "Option2": "France",
        "Option3": "Great Britain",
        "Option4": "Soviet Union",
        "Answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 78,
        "Question": "What was the main purpose of the 'Lebensraum' policy?",
        "Option1": "To exterminate all Jews",
        "Option2": "To create living space for Germans",
        "Option3": "To build a new navy",
        "Option4": "To establish colonies in Africa",
        "Answer": "To create living space for Germans"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 79,
        "Question": "Which country was NOT a permanent member of the United Nations Security Council after WWII?",
        "Option1": "United States",
        "Option2": "France",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 80,
        "Question": "What was the name of the second city hit by an atomic bomb?",
        "Option1": "Hiroshima",
        "Option2": "Tokyo",
        "Option3": "Nagasaki",
        "Option4": "Kyoto",
        "Answer": "Nagasaki"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 81,
        "Question": "What was the name of the final battle of WWI?",
        "Option1": "Battle of the Somme",
        "Option2": "Battle of Verdun",
        "Option3": "Hundred Days Offensive",
        "Option4": "Battle of the Marne",
        "Answer": "Hundred Days Offensive"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 82,
        "Question": "The 'Lost Generation' refers to the group of people who came of age during which war?",
        "Option1": "World War I",
        "Option2": "World War II",
        "Option3": "The Cold War",
        "Option4": "The Korean War",
        "Answer": "World War I"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 83,
        "Question": "What was the nickname for the American soldiers in WWI?",
        "Option1": "Yanks",
        "Option2": "Doughboys",
        "Option3": "GIs",
        "Option4": "Crusaders",
        "Answer": "Doughboys"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 84,
        "Question": "The Gallipoli Campaign was a failed military operation by the Allied Powers in which country?",
        "Option1": "Germany",
        "Option2": "Turkey",
        "Option3": "Italy",
        "Option4": "Russia",
        "Answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 85,
        "Question": "What was the name of the treaty that ended Russia's involvement in WWI?",
        "Option1": "Treaty of Versailles",
        "Option2": "Treaty of Brest-Litovsk",
        "Option3": "Treaty of Paris",
        "Option4": "Treaty of Trianon",
        "Answer": "Treaty of Brest-Litovsk"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 86,
        "Question": "Who was the United States President during WWI?",
        "Option1": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option2": "Theodore Roosevelt",
        "Option3": "Woodrow Wilson",
        "Option4": "Warren G. Harding",
        "Answer": "Woodrow Wilson"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 87,
        "Question": "The use of which weapon led to the end of open-field battles in WWI?",
        "Option1": "Poison gas",
        "Option2": "Tanks",
        "Option3": "Machine guns",
        "Option4": "Submarines",
        "Answer": "Machine guns"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 88,
        "Question": "What was the name of the British naval blockade of Germany during WWI?",
        "Option1": "The Allied Blockade",
        "Option2": "The Royal Navy Blockade",
        "Option3": "The Entente Blockade",
        "Option4": "The Continental Blockade",
        "Answer": "The Allied Blockade"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 89,
        "Question": "Which empire collapsed as a result of WWI?",
        "Option1": "The British Empire",
        "Option2": "The Russian Empire",
        "Option3": "The American Empire",
        "Option4": "The Roman Empire",
        "Answer": "The Russian Empire"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 90,
        "Question": "What was the main purpose of the League of Nations?",
        "Option1": "To promote international trade",
        "Option2": "To maintain world peace",
        "Option3": "To create a global army",
        "Option4": "To regulate global finance",
        "Answer": "To maintain world peace"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 91,
        "Question": "What was the name of the British code-breaking center during WWII?",
        "Option1": "The Pentagon",
        "Option2": "Bletchley Park",
        "Option3": "MI6",
        "Option4": "The Tower of London",
        "Answer": "Bletchley Park"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 92,
        "Question": "The Battle of Midway was a turning point in which theater of WWII?",
        "Option1": "European Theater",
        "Option2": "North African Theater",
        "Option3": "Pacific Theater",
        "Option4": "Eastern Front",
        "Answer": "Pacific Theater"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 93,
        "Question": "Who was the supreme commander of the Allied forces in the Pacific?",
        "Option1": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option2": "Douglas MacArthur",
        "Option3": "George Patton",
        "Option4": "Chester Nimitz",
        "Answer": "Douglas MacArthur"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 94,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German offensive to invade the Soviet Union?",
        "Option1": "Operation Sealion",
        "Option2": "Operation Torch",
        "Option3": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option4": "Operation Overlord",
        "Answer": "Operation Barbarossa"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 95,
        "Question": "What was the name of the US strategy of capturing key islands in the Pacific?",
        "Option1": "Blitzkrieg",
        "Option2": "Island hopping",
        "Option3": "Amphibious assault",
        "Option4": "Containment",
        "Answer": "Island hopping"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 96,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of the US during WWII for most of the war?",
        "Option1": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Option2": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option3": "Woodrow Wilson",
        "Option4": "Calvin Coolidge",
        "Answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 97,
        "Question": "What was the name of the famous speech given by Winston Churchill during the war?",
        "Option1": "The Gettysburg Address",
        "Option2": "The 'Iron Curtain' speech",
        "Option3": "The 'We Shall Fight on the Beaches' speech",
        "Option4": "The 'I Have a Dream' speech",
        "Answer": "The 'We Shall Fight on the Beaches' speech"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 98,
        "Question": "The Nuremberg Trials were held to prosecute what?",
        "Option1": "Japanese war criminals",
        "Option2": "German war criminals",
        "Option3": "Soviet spies",
        "Option4": "Italian Fascists",
        "Answer": "German war criminals"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 99,
        "Question": "What was the main purpose of the 'Anschluss'?",
        "Option1": "The union of Germany and Austria",
        "Option2": "The invasion of Poland",
        "Option3": "The creation of a new German army",
        "Option4": "The annexation of Czechoslovakia",
        "Answer": "The union of Germany and Austria"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 100,
        "Question": "The Battle of Britain was fought primarily over which country?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Germany",
        "Option3": "Great Britain",
        "Option4": "Soviet Union",
        "Answer": "Great Britain"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 101,
        "Question": "What was the name of the Japanese emperor during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Hirohito",
        "Option2": "Tojo",
        "Option3": "Meiji",
        "Option4": "Mutsuhito",
        "Answer": "Hirohito"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 102,
        "Question": "The Battle of El Alamein, a major battle in North Africa, was fought between which two forces?",
        "Option1": "British and German",
        "Option2": "US and Italian",
        "Option3": "Soviet and German",
        "Option4": "French and British",
        "Answer": "British and German"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 103,
        "Question": "What was the name of the organization that governed the Jewish ghettos under Nazi rule?",
        "Option1": "Gestapo",
        "Option2": "SS",
        "Option3": "Judenrat",
        "Option4": "Wehrmacht",
        "Answer": "Judenrat"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 104,
        "Question": "The term 'blitzkrieg' translates to what?",
        "Option1": "Lightning war",
        "Option2": "Total war",
        "Option3": "Trench war",
        "Option4": "Air war",
        "Answer": "Lightning war"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 105,
        "Question": "Which country was NOT a permanent member of the League of Nations' Council?",
        "Option1": "United States",
        "Option2": "Great Britain",
        "Option3": "France",
        "Option4": "Italy",
        "Answer": "United States"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 106,
        "Question": "The Battle of the Somme was a major battle on which front of WWI?",
        "Option1": "Eastern Front",
        "Option2": "Western Front",
        "Option3": "Italian Front",
        "Option4": "Balkan Front",
        "Answer": "Western Front"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 107,
        "Question": "Which country's navy was the most powerful at the start of WWI?",
        "Option1": "Germany",
        "Option2": "United States",
        "Option3": "Great Britain",
        "Option4": "Russia",
        "Answer": "Great Britain"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 108,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German submarine fleet?",
        "Option1": "Kriegsmarine",
        "Option2": "U-boats",
        "Option3": "Luftwaffe",
        "Option4": "Panzerwaffe",
        "Answer": "U-boats"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 109,
        "Question": "What was the main purpose of the 'War Guilt Clause' in the Treaty of Versailles?",
        "Option1": "To blame France for the war",
        "Option2": "To force Germany to accept sole responsibility for the war",
        "Option3": "To blame Russia for the war",
        "Option4": "To force Austria-Hungary to pay reparations",
        "Answer": "To force Germany to accept sole responsibility for the war"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 110,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German air raids on London during WWII?",
        "Option1": "The Blitz",
        "Option2": "The Blitzkrieg",
        "Option3": "Operation Sealion",
        "Option4": "Operation Overlord",
        "Answer": "The Blitz"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 111,
        "Question": "Which country's invasion of Poland started WWII?",
        "Option1": "Soviet Union",
        "Option2": "Italy",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Japan",
        "Answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 112,
        "Question": "The Japanese bombing of Pearl Harbor led to the US joining which war?",
        "Option1": "World War I",
        "Option2": "World War II",
        "Option3": "The Cold War",
        "Option4": "The Korean War",
        "Answer": "World War II"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 113,
        "Question": "What was the name of the British evacuation of Allied soldiers from France in 1940?",
        "Option1": "Operation Torch",
        "Option2": "The Dunkirk evacuation",
        "Option3": "Operation Overlord",
        "Option4": "The Battle of Britain",
        "Answer": "The Dunkirk evacuation"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 114,
        "Question": "The Battle of Stalingrad was a major defeat for which country?",
        "Option1": "Soviet Union",
        "Option2": "United States",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 115,
        "Question": "What was the name of the famous German tank commander in North Africa?",
        "Option1": "Erwin Rommel",
        "Option2": "Heinz Guderian",
        "Option3": "Erich von Manstein",
        "Option4": "Gerd von Rundstedt",
        "Answer": "Erwin Rommel"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 116,
        "Question": "The surrender of Japan was signed aboard which US ship?",
        "Option1": "USS Arizona",
        "Option2": "USS Missouri",
        "Option3": "USS Enterprise",
        "Option4": "USS Lexington",
        "Answer": "USS Missouri"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 117,
        "Question": "What was the main purpose of the 'Final Solution'?",
        "Option1": "To win the war quickly",
        "Option2": "To expand German territory",
        "Option3": "The Nazi plan to exterminate all Jews",
        "Option4": "To create a new form of government",
        "Answer": "The Nazi plan to exterminate all Jews"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 118,
        "Question": "Which of the following was a result of the Treaty of Versailles?",
        "Option1": "Germany was required to join the League of Nations",
        "Option2": "Germany's military was limited in size",
        "Option3": "Germany was allowed to keep its colonies",
        "Option4": "Germany was given control of France",
        "Answer": "Germany's military was limited in size"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 119,
        "Question": "What was the name of the British leader who signed the Munich Agreement, practicing appeasement?",
        "Option1": "Winston Churchill",
        "Option2": "Neville Chamberlain",
        "Option3": "Clement Attlee",
        "Option4": "Lloyd George",
        "Answer": "Neville Chamberlain"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 120,
        "Question": "The Battle of Midway was fought primarily with what?",
        "Option1": "Tanks",
        "Option2": "Ships",
        "Option3": "Aircraft carriers and aircraft",
        "Option4": "Submarines",
        "Answer": "Aircraft carriers and aircraft"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 121,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German defense line on the Western Front in WWI?",
        "Option1": "Maginot Line",
        "Option2": "Siegfried Line",
        "Option3": "Hindenburg Line",
        "Option4": "Atlantic Wall",
        "Answer": "Hindenburg Line"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 122,
        "Question": "The sinking of the Lusitania was a major reason for which country's entry into WWI?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Russia",
        "Option3": "United States",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "United States"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 123,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German general who was the commander of the Afrika Korps?",
        "Option1": "Heinz Guderian",
        "Option2": "Erwin Rommel",
        "Option3": "Gerd von Rundstedt",
        "Option4": "Erich von Manstein",
        "Answer": "Erwin Rommel"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 124,
        "Question": "The Battle of the Marne in WWI was significant because it halted what?",
        "Option1": "The Russian advance",
        "Option2": "The German advance on Paris",
        "Option3": "The British naval blockade",
        "Option4": "The Ottoman invasion",
        "Answer": "The German advance on Paris"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 125,
        "Question": "What was the main purpose of the 'Anschluss'?",
        "Option1": "The union of Germany and Austria",
        "Option2": "The invasion of Poland",
        "Option3": "The creation of a new German army",
        "Option4": "The annexation of Czechoslovakia",
        "Answer": "The union of Germany and Austria"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 126,
        "Question": "Which of the following was a new weapon used in WWI?",
        "Option1": "Crossbows",
        "Option2": "Poison gas",
        "Option3": "Cannons",
        "Option4": "Flamethrowers",
        "Answer": "Poison gas"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 127,
        "Question": "What was the name of the peace-keeping organization formed after WWI?",
        "Option1": "United Nations",
        "Option2": "League of Nations",
        "Option3": "NATO",
        "Option4": "Red Cross",
        "Answer": "League of Nations"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 128,
        "Question": "The term 'no man's land' refers to the area between which two WWI military positions?",
        "Option1": "The fronts of two navies",
        "Option2": "The lines of opposing trenches",
        "Option3": "The sky between two air forces",
        "Option4": "The land between two countries",
        "Answer": "The lines of opposing trenches"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 129,
        "Question": "Which nation was NOT a part of the Central Powers during WWI?",
        "Option1": "Austria-Hungary",
        "Option2": "Germany",
        "Option3": "Ottoman Empire",
        "Option4": "Italy",
        "Answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 130,
        "Question": "What was the date of the armistice that ended the fighting in WWI?",
        "Option1": "December 25, 1918",
        "Option2": "November 11, 1918",
        "Option3": "October 31, 1918",
        "Option4": "January 1, 1919",
        "Answer": "November 11, 1918"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 131,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German war plan for WWI?",
        "Option1": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option2": "Schlieffen Plan",
        "Option3": "Operation Overlord",
        "Option4": "The Battle of Britain",
        "Answer": "Schlieffen Plan"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 132,
        "Question": "The Treaty of Versailles required Germany to pay large sums of money, known as what?",
        "Option1": "Taxes",
        "Option2": "Reparations",
        "Option3": "Tariffs",
        "Option4": "Bonds",
        "Answer": "Reparations"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 133,
        "Question": "What major event happened in Russia during WWI that led to its withdrawal from the war?",
        "Option1": "A civil war",
        "Option2": "The Bolshevik Revolution",
        "Option3": "A military coup",
        "Option4": "A famine",
        "Answer": "The Bolshevik Revolution"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 134,
        "Question": "The sinking of which British ocean liner by a German U-boat in 1915 angered the United States?",
        "Option1": "Titanic",
        "Option2": "Queen Mary",
        "Option3": "Lusitania",
        "Option4": "Britannic",
        "Answer": "Lusitania"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 135,
        "Question": "What new technology was first used on a large scale in WWI?",
        "Option1": "The nuclear bomb",
        "Option2": "The radar",
        "Option3": "Tanks",
        "Option4": "Submarines",
        "Answer": "Tanks"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 136,
        "Question": "Which country was NOT a member of the Triple Entente in World War I?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Russia",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 137,
        "Question": "The attack on Pearl Harbor happened on what date?",
        "Option1": "December 7, 1941",
        "Option2": "June 6, 1944",
        "Option3": "September 1, 1939",
        "Option4": "May 8, 1945",
        "Answer": "December 7, 1941"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 138,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of the Soviet Union during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option2": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option3": "Leon Trotsky",
        "Option4": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Answer": "Joseph Stalin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 139,
        "Question": "Which country was NOT a member of the Axis Powers?",
        "Option1": "Germany",
        "Option2": "Japan",
        "Option3": "Italy",
        "Option4": "Soviet Union",
        "Answer": "Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 140,
        "Question": "The D-Day invasion took place on which beach?",
        "Option1": "Omaha Beach",
        "Option2": "Iwo Jima",
        "Option3": "Normandy Beach",
        "Option4": "Pebble Beach",
        "Answer": "Normandy Beach"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 141,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German Air Force during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Panzerwaffe",
        "Option2": "Kriegsmarine",
        "Option3": "Luftwaffe",
        "Option4": "Wehrmacht",
        "Answer": "Luftwaffe"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 142,
        "Question": "The Battle of Britain was fought primarily with what?",
        "Option1": "Tanks",
        "Option2": "Ships",
        "Option3": "Submarines",
        "Option4": "Aircraft",
        "Answer": "Aircraft"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 143,
        "Question": "What was the term for Germany's lightning-fast military strategy?",
        "Option1": "Sitzkrieg",
        "Option2": "Blitzkrieg",
        "Option3": "Lebensraum",
        "Option4": "Anschluss",
        "Answer": "Blitzkrieg"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 144,
        "Question": "Who was the Prime Minister of Great Britain during most of WWII?",
        "Option1": "Neville Chamberlain",
        "Option2": "Winston Churchill",
        "Option3": "Clement Attlee",
        "Option4": "Tony Blair",
        "Answer": "Winston Churchill"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 145,
        "Question": "The Manhattan Project was the code name for the development of what?",
        "Option1": "The Enigma machine",
        "Option2": "The atomic bomb",
        "Option3": "Jet engines",
        "Option4": "Radar technology",
        "Answer": "The atomic bomb"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 146,
        "Question": "What was the name of the final major German offensive on the Western Front in WWII?",
        "Option1": "Battle of the Bulge",
        "Option2": "Battle of Normandy",
        "Option3": "Battle of the Ruhr",
        "Option4": "Battle of Stalingrad",
        "Answer": "Battle of the Bulge"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 147,
        "Question": "Which city was the first to be hit by an atomic bomb?",
        "Option1": "Tokyo",
        "Option2": "Hiroshima",
        "Option3": "Nagasaki",
        "Option4": "Kyoto",
        "Answer": "Hiroshima"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 148,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German invasion of the Soviet Union?",
        "Option1": "Operation Sealion",
        "Option2": "Operation Torch",
        "Option3": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option4": "Operation Overlord",
        "Answer": "Operation Barbarossa"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 149,
        "Question": "Which country signed a non-aggression pact with Nazi Germany in 1939, only to be invaded later?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Poland",
        "Option3": "Soviet Union",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 150,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German air raids on British cities during WWII?",
        "Option1": "The Blitz",
        "Option2": "The Pounding",
        "Option3": "The Storm",
        "Option4": "The Bombardment",
        "Answer": "The Blitz"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 151,
        "Question": "Who was the US President who authorized the use of atomic bombs on Japan?",
        "Option1": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option2": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Option3": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option4": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Answer": "Harry S. Truman"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 152,
        "Question": "The policy of appeasement was primarily aimed at avoiding war with which country?",
        "Option1": "Italy",
        "Option2": "Japan",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Soviet Union",
        "Answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 153,
        "Question": "Which of the following was a new invention that helped the British in the Battle of Britain?",
        "Option1": "Radar",
        "Option2": "Jet engines",
        "Option3": "Nuclear submarines",
        "Option4": "Stealth bombers",
        "Answer": "Radar"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 154,
        "Question": "What was the name of the first concentration camp established by the Nazis?",
        "Option1": "Auschwitz",
        "Option2": "Dachau",
        "Option3": "Treblinka",
        "Option4": "Sachsenhausen",
        "Answer": "Dachau"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 155,
        "Question": "What was the name of the first concentration camp established by the Nazis?",
        "Option1": "Auschwitz",
        "Option2": "Dachau",
        "Option3": "Treblinka",
        "Option4": "Sachsenhausen",
        "Answer": "Dachau"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 156,
        "Question": "Which country signed a non-aggression pact with Nazi Germany in 1939, only to be invaded later?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Poland",
        "Option3": "Soviet Union",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 157,
        "Question": "The Battle of Stalingrad was a turning point on which front?",
        "Option1": "Western Front",
        "Option2": "Eastern Front",
        "Option3": "Pacific Front",
        "Option4": "African Front",
        "Answer": "Eastern Front"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 158,
        "Question": "What was the name of the major naval battle in the Pacific theater between the US and Japan?",
        "Option1": "Battle of the Atlantic",
        "Option2": "Battle of Midway",
        "Option3": "Battle of the Coral Sea",
        "Option4": "Battle of Okinawa",
        "Answer": "Battle of Midway"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 159,
        "Question": "The genocide of approximately six million Jews by the Nazi regime is known as what?",
        "Option1": "The Great Purge",
        "Option2": "The Holocaust",
        "Option3": "The Final Solution",
        "Option4": "The Great Famine",
        "Answer": "The Holocaust"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 160,
        "Question": "Which city was the site of the war crimes tribunals after WWII?",
        "Option1": "Paris",
        "Option2": "London",
        "Option3": "Nuremberg",
        "Option4": "Tokyo",
        "Answer": "Nuremberg"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 161,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German defense line on the French coast?",
        "Option1": "Maginot Line",
        "Option2": "Siegfried Line",
        "Option3": "Atlantic Wall",
        "Option4": "Gustav Line",
        "Answer": "Atlantic Wall"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 162,
        "Question": "Who was the Supreme Commander of the Allied Expeditionary Force in Europe during WWII?",
        "Option1": "George S. Patton",
        "Option2": "Douglas MacArthur",
        "Option3": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option4": "Bernard Montgomery",
        "Answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 163,
        "Question": "What was the name of the Allied invasion of North Africa in WWII?",
        "Option1": "Operation Torch",
        "Option2": "Operation Overlord",
        "Option3": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option4": "Operation Sealion",
        "Answer": "Operation Torch"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 164,
        "Question": "The Japanese surrender in WWII was signed aboard which US battleship?",
        "Option1": "USS Arizona",
        "Option2": "USS Missouri",
        "Option3": "USS Enterprise",
        "Option4": "USS Lexington",
        "Answer": "USS Missouri"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 165,
        "Question": "What was the term for the period after the German invasion of Poland when there was little fighting?",
        "Option1": "Blitzkrieg",
        "Option2": "Sitzkrieg",
        "Option3": "Phony War",
        "Option4": "Stalingrad",
        "Answer": "Phony War"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 166,
        "Question": "The Battle of Stalingrad was fought in which country?",
        "Option1": "Germany",
        "Option2": "Poland",
        "Option3": "Soviet Union",
        "Option4": "France",
        "Answer": "Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 167,
        "Question": "Who was the US President who authorized the use of atomic bombs on Japan?",
        "Option1": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option2": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Option3": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option4": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Answer": "Harry S. Truman"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 168,
        "Question": "What was the main purpose of the United Nations, founded after WWII?",
        "Option1": "To create a global currency",
        "Option2": "To prevent future wars",
        "Option3": "To control global trade",
        "Option4": "To promote specific political ideologies",
        "Answer": "To prevent future wars"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 169,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German invasion of the Soviet Union?",
        "Option1": "Operation Sealion",
        "Option2": "Operation Torch",
        "Option3": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option4": "Operation Overlord",
        "Answer": "Operation Barbarossa"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 170,
        "Question": "Which country signed a non-aggression pact with Nazi Germany in 1939, only to be invaded later?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Poland",
        "Option3": "Soviet Union",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 171,
        "Question": "The Battle of the Bulge took place in which country?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Belgium",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Soviet Union",
        "Answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 172,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of the Fascist Party in Italy?",
        "Option1": "Adolf Hitler",
        "Option2": "Benito Mussolini",
        "Option3": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option4": "Francisco Franco",
        "Answer": "Benito Mussolini"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 173,
        "Question": "The 'Maginot Line' was a series of fortifications built by which country?",
        "Option1": "Germany",
        "Option2": "France",
        "Option3": "Great Britain",
        "Option4": "Soviet Union",
        "Answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 174,
        "Question": "What was the main purpose of the 'Lebensraum' policy?",
        "Option1": "To exterminate all Jews",
        "Option2": "To create living space for Germans",
        "Option3": "To build a new navy",
        "Option4": "To establish colonies in Africa",
        "Answer": "To create living space for Germans"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 175,
        "Question": "Which country was NOT a permanent member of the United Nations Security Council after WWII?",
        "Option1": "United States",
        "Option2": "France",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 176,
        "Question": "What was the name of the second city hit by an atomic bomb?",
        "Option1": "Hiroshima",
        "Option2": "Tokyo",
        "Option3": "Nagasaki",
        "Option4": "Kyoto",
        "Answer": "Nagasaki"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 177,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German secret police during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Gestapo",
        "Option2": "SS",
        "Option3": "SA",
        "Option4": "Wehrmacht",
        "Answer": "Gestapo"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 178,
        "Question": "The Battle of the Atlantic was fought primarily between whom?",
        "Option1": "British and German naval forces",
        "Option2": "US and Japanese naval forces",
        "Option3": "German and Soviet forces",
        "Option4": "British and French forces",
        "Answer": "British and German naval forces"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 179,
        "Question": "What was the code name for the D-Day invasion?",
        "Option1": "Operation Torch",
        "Option2": "Operation Overlord",
        "Option3": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option4": "Operation Sealion",
        "Answer": "Operation Overlord"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 180,
        "Question": "What was the name of the Italian dictator during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Benito Mussolini",
        "Option2": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option3": "Francisco Franco",
        "Option4": "Antonio Salazar",
        "Answer": "Benito Mussolini"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 181,
        "Question": "Which country was the first to successfully develop a nuclear weapon?",
        "Option1": "Soviet Union",
        "Option2": "Great Britain",
        "Option3": "United States",
        "Option4": "Germany",
        "Answer": "United States"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 182,
        "Question": "The United States provided war materials to Allied nations through what program before officially entering WWII?",
        "Option1": "The Marshall Plan",
        "Option2": "The Lend-Lease Act",
        "Option3": "The Monroe Doctrine",
        "Option4": "The Fourteen Points",
        "Answer": "The Lend-Lease Act"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 183,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German-speaking area of Czechoslovakia that Hitler demanded?",
        "Option1": "The Rhineland",
        "Option2": "The Sudetenland",
        "Option3": "The Polish Corridor",
        "Option4": "The Baltic States",
        "Answer": "The Sudetenland"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 184,
        "Question": "The Battle of the Bulge took place in which country?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Belgium",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Soviet Union",
        "Answer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 185,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German war plan for WWI?",
        "Option1": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option2": "Schlieffen Plan",
        "Option3": "Operation Overlord",
        "Option4": "The Battle of Britain",
        "Answer": "Schlieffen Plan"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 186,
        "Question": "The Treaty of Versailles required Germany to pay large sums of money, known as what?",
        "Option1": "Taxes",
        "Option2": "Reparations",
        "Option3": "Tariffs",
        "Option4": "Bonds",
        "Answer": "Reparations"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 187,
        "Question": "What major event happened in Russia during WWI that led to its withdrawal from the war?",
        "Option1": "A civil war",
        "Option2": "The Bolshevik Revolution",
        "Option3": "A military coup",
        "Option4": "A famine",
        "Answer": "The Bolshevik Revolution"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 188,
        "Question": "The sinking of which British ocean liner by a German U-boat in 1915 angered the United States?",
        "Option1": "Titanic",
        "Option2": "Queen Mary",
        "Option3": "Lusitania",
        "Option4": "Britannic",
        "Answer": "Lusitania"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 189,
        "Question": "What new technology was first used on a large scale in WWI?",
        "Option1": "The nuclear bomb",
        "Option2": "The radar",
        "Option3": "Tanks",
        "Option4": "Submarines",
        "Answer": "Tanks"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 190,
        "Question": "Which country was NOT a member of the Triple Entente in World War I?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Russia",
        "Option3": "Germany",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "Germany"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 191,
        "Question": "The attack on Pearl Harbor happened on what date?",
        "Option1": "December 7, 1941",
        "Option2": "June 6, 1944",
        "Option3": "September 1, 1939",
        "Option4": "May 8, 1945",
        "Answer": "December 7, 1941"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 192,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of the Soviet Union during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option2": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option3": "Leon Trotsky",
        "Option4": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Answer": "Joseph Stalin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 193,
        "Question": "Which country was NOT a member of the Axis Powers?",
        "Option1": "Germany",
        "Option2": "Japan",
        "Option3": "Italy",
        "Option4": "Soviet Union",
        "Answer": "Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 194,
        "Question": "The D-Day invasion took place on which beach?",
        "Option1": "Omaha Beach",
        "Option2": "Iwo Jima",
        "Option3": "Normandy Beach",
        "Option4": "Pebble Beach",
        "Answer": "Normandy Beach"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 195,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German Air Force during WWII?",
        "Option1": "Panzerwaffe",
        "Option2": "Kriegsmarine",
        "Option3": "Luftwaffe",
        "Option4": "Wehrmacht",
        "Answer": "Luftwaffe"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 196,
        "Question": "The Battle of Britain was fought primarily with what?",
        "Option1": "Tanks",
        "Option2": "Ships",
        "Option3": "Submarines",
        "Option4": "Aircraft",
        "Answer": "Aircraft"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 197,
        "Question": "What was the term for Germany's lightning-fast military strategy?",
        "Option1": "Sitzkrieg",
        "Option2": "Blitzkrieg",
        "Option3": "Lebensraum",
        "Option4": "Anschluss",
        "Answer": "Blitzkrieg"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 198,
        "Question": "Who was the Prime Minister of Great Britain during most of WWII?",
        "Option1": "Neville Chamberlain",
        "Option2": "Winston Churchill",
        "Option3": "Clement Attlee",
        "Option4": "Tony Blair",
        "Answer": "Winston Churchill"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 199,
        "Question": "The Manhattan Project was the code name for the development of what?",
        "Option1": "The Enigma machine",
        "Option2": "The atomic bomb",
        "Option3": "Jet engines",
        "Option4": "Radar technology",
        "Answer": "The atomic bomb"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 200,
        "Question": "What was the name of the final major German offensive on the Western Front in WWII?",
        "Option1": "Battle of the Bulge",
        "Option2": "Battle of Normandy",
        "Option3": "Battle of the Ruhr",
        "Option4": "Battle of Stalingrad",
        "Answer": "Battle of the Bulge"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 201,
        "Question": "Which city was the first to be hit by an atomic bomb?",
        "Option1": "Tokyo",
        "Option2": "Hiroshima",
        "Option3": "Nagasaki",
        "Option4": "Kyoto",
        "Answer": "Hiroshima"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 202,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German invasion of the Soviet Union?",
        "Option1": "Operation Sealion",
        "Option2": "Operation Torch",
        "Option3": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option4": "Operation Overlord",
        "Answer": "Operation Barbarossa"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 203,
        "Question": "Which country signed a non-aggression pact with Nazi Germany in 1939, only to be invaded later?",
        "Option1": "France",
        "Option2": "Poland",
        "Option3": "Soviet Union",
        "Option4": "Great Britain",
        "Answer": "Soviet Union"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 204,
        "Question": "What was the name of the German air raids on British cities during WWII?",
        "Option1": "The Blitz",
        "Option2": "The Pounding",
        "Option3": "The Storm",
        "Option4": "The Bombardment",
        "Answer": "The Blitz"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 205,
        "Question": "What event brought the US into World War II?",
        "Option1": "The sinking of the Lusitania",
        "Option2": "The attack on Pearl Harbor",
        "Option3": "The invasion of Poland",
        "Option4": "The Battle of Britain",
        "Answer": "The attack on Pearl Harbor"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 206,
        "Question": "The Battle of Normandy is also known as what?",
        "Option1": "Operation Torch",
        "Option2": "Operation Overlord",
        "Option3": "Operation Barbarossa",
        "Option4": "The Battle of the Bulge",
        "Answer": "Operation Overlord"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 207,
        "Question": "Which Axis country surrendered first in WWII?",
        "Option1": "Germany",
        "Option2": "Italy",
        "Option3": "Japan",
        "Option4": "Hungary",
        "Answer": "Italy"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 208,
        "Question": "The Yalta Conference involved the leaders of which three countries?",
        "Option1": "United States, Soviet Union, Great Britain",
        "Option2": "Germany, Italy, Japan",
        "Option3": "United States, France, Italy",
        "Option4": "Germany, United States, Great Britain",
        "Answer": "United States, Soviet Union, Great Britain"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 209,
        "Question": "What was the purpose of the 'Final Solution'?",
        "Option1": "To win the war quickly",
        "Option2": "To expand German territory",
        "Option3": "The Nazi plan to exterminate all Jews",
        "Option4": "To create a new form of government",
        "Answer": "The Nazi plan to exterminate all Jews"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 210,
        "Question": "The Berlin airlift was a post-WWII event that took place in which city?",
        "Option1": "Berlin",
        "Option2": "London",
        "Option3": "Moscow",
        "Option4": "Paris",
        "Answer": "Berlin"
    }
]